Long ago, in ancient China,
好耐以前蝶中原…
the Peacocks ruled over Gongmen City.
孔汰一族统治宫门城
They brought great joy and prosperity to the city
为全城带嗓坎乐、繁荣
for they had invented fireworks.
因为但吡发明虹… 类火
But their son, Lord Shen,
不过伍吨后人沈老大…
saw darker power in the fireworks.
识得利用粳火咀险暗面
What had brought color and joy
令原本带喉色彩、获纪咀类火
could also bring darkness and destruction.
亦得那恶、充满破坏力
Shen's troubled parents consulted a soothsayer.
沈老大父母好担心 去请教天机女
She foretold that if Shen continued down this dark path,
仁预言沈老大继续为非作丈…
he would be defeated by a warrior of black and white.
最终会界一个黑白战士打低
The young ford set out fo change his fate.
年轻最沈老大决心改变命运
But what he did next only sealed it.
结果反而走上不如路
Shen returned to his parents full of pride.
沈老大满怀自信返去见父母
But in their faces, he saw only horror.
但只见伍吡满面恐必
He was banished from the city forever.
伍被赶出城，永下放逐
But Shen swore revenge.
沈老大发拆报仇
Someday he would return
终有一日要返屋企
and all of China would bow at his feet.
仲要全中原跪拜但
It's almost done, Lord Shen, but we've run out of metal.
就完成，沈老大，但唔级钢铁
Search the farthest villages! Find more metal!
去偏下村甘搜掠! 揭更多钢氏!
China will be mine.
中原好快会属於我!
And then the Dragon Warrior joined the Furious Five!
之后龙战士同盖世五侠联手
And they became the most awesomest kung fu team ever!
成为史上最拓咀武林侠客!
Enough talk. Let's fight!
废话少讲! 决六啦!
- Thirty-three... - Listen, listen!
革吓!
You can hear the Dragon Warrior training right now!
职得出傈龙战士特训紧!
Thirty-three. Stop him!
331! 咪界伍再塞较!
- Thirty-four. - It's too dangerous!
太危阶!
- Thirty-five. Stay focused. - Thirty-six!
集中! 36 !
- Thirty-seven! - Yeah!
37!
How is he doing that with his face?
点解伍才面只都得?
Thirty-eight bean buns!
38个豆沙包!
Yes! New record! You monster!
好喇! 新纪俏! 你焦怪物!
- Keep going! Hit 40! - He'll never hit 40.
继续! 挑战40! 便实唔得
You guys wait and we'll go to 40.
你噶等等，我会塞级40个
Do it.
做咱 !
No problem!
右间题!
Give me a minute.
等等!
- He did it! - Well done, Po!
伍得咏! 好喇，阿宽!
Your training has paid off.
你咀训张右白导
Master Shifu! Gotta go. See you later!
施福师傅! 我要走啦! 一阵见!
You'll save those for me, right?
你吡会留返哟包界我?
Inner peace.
心平气和
Master Shifu.
施福师傅!
Master Shifu, what do we got?
施福上师传!: 有了只事?
Pirates? Vandals of Volcano Mountain?
海盗?火山派嘎火狂?
Whatever it is, I will take them down. ‘Cause I am in a mood.
只都好，实搞拓 我已经做足准人备
I need to get something done, you know what I mean?
点都要做吓咖，你明啦?
What are you doing?
你做呼呀?
One of Master Oogway's final teachings.
傈胡贵大师最最后教诲之一
Awesome!
好扩!
How did you do that?
你烛做到?
- Inner peace. - Inner piece. That's cool.
心平气和 心平气和，真傈劲
- Inner piece of what? - It is the next phase of your training.
心口要平成点? 你跟住就要修冻
Every master must find his path to inner peace.
每个大师都要提出自己 心平气和之道
Some choose to meditate for 50 years in a cave just like this...
有哟会吃山洞入面 冥想50年…
.. without the slightest taste of food or water.
完全唔搞食物同水
Or?
其他呢?
Some find it through pain and suffering, as I did.
有哟从苦难中领悟 好似我!
Po, the day you were chosen as Dragon Warrior
阿实，你当园龙战士…
was the worst day of my life.
傈我成世最痛苦最一日
By far. Nothing else came close.
至今都有其他事比得上
It was the worst, most painful, mind-destroying, horrible moment...
咽阵好摊命、好痛苦 头都谷爆…
- OK. -..[ have ever experienced.
得嘲 傈我经历过最惨晟时刻
But once I realized the problem was not you, but within me,
但当我明白问题喇傈你 傈我内心
I found inner peace and was able to harness the flow of the universe.
我就领悟心平气和之道 可以挪移天地之氟
So that's it? I just need inner peace?
就傈听? 我泽傈要心平气和?
My innards are already super, super peaceful,
我心肝脾肺袁都超级平和…
so alll need to do is just get this thing going.
即傈我只要顺住去就得
Inner peace, you're going down.
心平气和，我实搞扩你
Now show me what you were doing there with your feet.
界我嫉吓你焦脚
I saw you do sort of a fancy foot...
咽招犀利
Po! Bandits! Approaching the Musicians Village.
阿实! 有虹! 去紧乐归呀村甘
Danger.
有危险
Tell those musicians to start playing some action music because it is on.
叫班乐师演奏武打片配乐 因为就快天战!
Don't worry, Shifu, I'll master inner peace as soon as I get back.
唔使愁 我返噬就搞搞心平气和
No snack stops this time.
今次唔准停低食零食
Snack stops.
停低食零食
Wait, are you serious?
咪住，你讲真?
Get all the metal you can find!
搬晒所有钢铁!
Grab the metal!
去扒钢氏!
Help, help, help, help. Help!
救命! 救命!
That's everything! Let's get out of here.
只都搬晒! 散水啦!
Wings of Justice!
大侠展翅!
The Dragon Warrior!
龙战士!
A panda? That's impossible.
傈熊猫? 有可能!
My fist hungers for justice.
我对正义拳俄咏好耐
That was my... fist.
咽哟傈…拳风声
- Get ‘em! - Come on!
对付但呈! 噬呼!
Take that!
接招!
Po! Incoming!
阿实! 小心!
Thanks, Mantis!
唔该，猛星螂!
Tigress, Double Death Strike!
和飞虎女，春命思环诀 !
Feet of Fury!
精武肥毛腿!
Tigress! Monkey!
飞虎女! 里猴!
Viper! Mantis!
毒蛇! 猛螃螂!
Bunny! What?
免仔! 号?
Oh, sorry.
唔好意思!
Help!
救命!
- Crane, go! -I'm on it!
仙笨，上呀! 我会搞拓
Is everyone OK?
大家有事嘛?
That was awesome!
真傈好拓!
I got this.
等我只咬!
Po!
阿实!
Chew on that, tubby!
硬食咬你，大肚杰!
- Sweetie, are you OK? - What happened?
你右事嘛? 发生只事呀?
I think I saw...
我论我见到…
I gotta go.
我要走
Thank you. Thank you for coming to Dragon Warrior Noodles and Tofu.
欢迎光临龙战士豆腐菇种
- More tea? Lemon sauce? - No.
加茶? 甜酸警?
If you need anything, just ask.
要只即管天声
- Thank you. - Feet of Fury!
多谢 精武肥毛腿!
The Dragon Warrior's mop. He mopped these very floors!
龙战士用过咀地拖! 但用唉拖呢块地 !
No touching! You'll get the mop dirty.
唔好搞! 会整污粮把地拖!
- He once waited on me. - Awesome!
伍招呼过我 拓!
Yeah, I have the stain to prove it. Hey, where is the Dragon Warrior?
我件衫搓渍可以证明 龙战士呢?
He doesn't work here anymore.
但而家唔吃度做咖
He's busy out there protecting the Valley.
但忙住保护太平谷
- The Dragon Warrior! - There he is.
龙战士!
Po!
阿实!
- Here. OK. Nice kid. - The Dragon Warrior!
噬啦 好，乖
- Should've told me you were coming. - Hi, Dad.
你返噬应该早哟讲 阿驳
I would have saved you some stinky tofu.
等我留定哟臭豆腐界你
- Dad, can I talk to you? - Of course, son.
阿驳，倾吓得嘛? 梗得啦，乖仔
In honor of my son, free tofu dessert for everybody!
我乖仔万莽，请大家食豆腐花
With purchases.
有点菜先有得食
Oh, it's so good to see you, Po.
见到你就开心，阿实
Have you lost weight? I can almost put my wings around you.
你轻咕? 我对恤差响围得住你条腰
Ah, well, maybe a little.
或者有啦
Poor you, you must feel weak. Let me get you some soup.
你一定好锥扭，我择渴界你饮
No, that's OK, Dad. I'm not hungry.
唔使，我唔肚饭
Not hungry? Po, are you all right?
唔肚化? 阿实，你有右事?
Yeah. No, I'm fine. I just...
右事，只傈…
Earlier today, I was fighting these bandits.
头先我去对付班贼
Nothing too dangerous. I mean, they were just, you know...
右世危险 伍吨只傈…
- Yeah? - And then the strangest thing happened.
奇在发生嘎件事
I had this crazy vision.
我有幻觉
I think l saw my mom and me, as a baby.
我见到我娘亲 仲有我苏昭仔咽柑
Mom? A baby?
娘亲? 苏昭仔?
- Dad? - What...?
阿驳? 你究竟想讲只?
How do I say this?
点讲好呢?
Where did I come from?
我由净度喉?
Well, you see, son, baby geese come from a little egg.
你知了，乖仔… 匾仔傈由义和蛋旷出嗓
- Don't ask where the egg comes from. - Dad, that's not what I meant.
唔好问我勺蛋由净度咯 阿驳，我唔傈听意思
I know it's not.
我知唔傈
I think it’s time I told you something I should have told you a long time ago.
我论傈时候讲你知… 我应该早就讲
OK.
好!
You might have been kind of a...
其实你只算傈…
..adopted.
头子
- 1 knew it. - You knew?
我知 你知?
- Well, who told you? - No one. I mean, come on, Dad.
净个讲你知? 右! 仲使讲? 阿驳
But if you knew, why didn't you ever say anything?
你一早知又喇提”?
Why didn't you say anything?
你又唔提?
How did I get here, Dad? Where did I come from?
我点唉呢度? 由净度嗓?
Actually... you came from this.
老实讲… 你由呢度唉
It was just another day at the restaurant.
咽日同平时一柑
Time to make the noodles.
我准备开档整基
! went out to the back, where my vegetables had just been delivered.
我去后面想氛新鲜送到吕蔬菜
There were cabbages, turnips, radishes.
傈椰菜、大白菜同药葡
Only there were no radishes.
但傈入面右药葡…
Just a very hungry baby panda.
得焦肚侯熊猪仔
There was no note.
揭唔到字休
Of course, you could have eaten it.
有可能傈你食咏
! waited for someone to come looking for you, but no one did.
我吃度等你亲属只揭你 但一直等喇到
! brought you inside.
我带你入嗓
Fed you.
猿你
Gave you a bath.
于你溃泳
And fed you again.
又再银你
And again.
再银你
And tried to put some pants on you.
仲试过想景你著裤
And then I made a decision that would change my life forever.
跟住我做喧个改变一生吕决定
To make my soup without radishes.
者渴咽阵唔落巩和萄
And to raise you as my own son.
同埋将你沼傈我自己个仔
Xiao Po, my little panda.
小实，我咀小能和猿
And from that moment on, both my soup and my life
之后，我咀渴同生命…
have been that much sweeter.
都释得更加甜
And, little Po, that's the end of the story.
小实，成件事就傈只
Look at me. No, don't look at me.
嫉吓我，喇好，都傈唔好望
That's it? That can't be it. There's gotta be more, Dad!
就傈听? 右可能，应该促有嚼，阿驳
Well, there was the time you ate all my bamboo furniture.
傈，有次你食晒我响竹秽像仿
It was imported, too.
仲傈进口货
One dumpling, please, Dragon Warrior size.
一焦饺子，特大龙战士装
Oh, Po, your story may not have such a happy beginning,
你骂故事开头可能唔多开心…
but look how it turned out.
但你嫉吓而家点?
You got me, you got kung fu, and you got noodles.
你有我，有功夫，仲有得食莉
I know. I just have so many questions.
我知，但我休有好多问题
Like how did I ever fit in this tiny basket?
点解我会塞得落个篮?
Why didn't I like pants?
点解我喇锤意著裤?
And who am I?
究竟我傈净个?
Good. Watch your form.
好，注意你咀架式
Good.
好
Shen?
沈老大?
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
各位，午安
Now we've got the pleasantries out of the way, please leave my house.
击场白讲完 请你吡离开我屋企
- Your house? - Yes.
你屋企? 傈
Didn't you see the peacock on the front door?
你吡喇见正门有焦孔和省?
There you are, Soothsayer.
你喉度，天机女
It seems your fortune-telling skills are not as good as you thought.
似乎你明占下能力 右你想像只团
- We shall see, Shen. - No, you shall see, old goat.
嫉吓点，沈老大 你嫉咬! 老喇!
- Where were we? - What do you want, Shen?
讲到冰度? 你想点?
What is rightfully mine. Gongmen City!
氛返属於我咀喇 富上门城
Gongmen is under the stewardship of the Masters’ Council,
宫门城由我吡武林联盟保护
and we will protect it. Even from you.
唔会交界你
I'm so glad you feel that way.
好在你啦论
Otherwise, I'd have dragged that here for nothing.
唔傈我只辛苦拖但喉就白疆
What's in the box, Shen?
箱入面有了呼?
You want to see? It's a gift.
你想嫉? 傈份礼物
It's your parting gift, in that it will part you.
纪念同你分天 即傈话佰会将你分并
Part of you here, part of you there
一忽喉呢度，一忽喉咽度
and part of you way over there, staining the wall!
一忽飞到和踪一下，秋住幅粳
You insolent fool!
好一个无也狂徒!
- Show-off. - That is a warning.
你演吵! 傈警告
You are no match for our kung fu.
你吕功夫赢唔到我哟
l agree.
我同意
But this is.
但傈但赢到
Are you familiar with the master of Gongmen City?
你识喇识言门城城主?
- Master Thundering Rhino? - Yes.
雷霆犀牛大师? 傈
- Son of legendary Flying Rhino?
犀科利牛师苯个仔?
And slayer of the Ten Thousand Serpents in the Valley of Woe?
喉万劳谷斩杀万人条蛇妖响个?
- He's dead. - Whoa.
伍死咏 哇!
That's impossible.
右可能!
Rhino's Horn Defense is impervious to any technique.
仁咀牛角访身术唔怕任何招数
It was no technique. Lord Shen has created a weapon,
唔傈招数 沈老大秽造咏件武器
one that breathes fire and spits metal.
会吞吐火始，喷出铁弹
Unless he is stopped, this could be the end of kung fu.
唔制止但…功夫就会被减绝
- But I just got kung fu! - And now you must save it.
我吵哎至学识功夫 所以你要维访住
Go! Destroy this weapon and bring Lord Shen to justice!
去啦! 毁沽件武器 制裁沈老大
OK, here we go! Here we go!
好，出发!
Wait a second. How can I! do this?
咪住先，我点搞得扯?
I mean, how can kung fu stop something that stops kung fu?
点用功夫去圳制 会均制功夫咕喇?
Remember, Dragon Warrior,
记住
anything is possible when you have inner peace.
你识心平气和就昱都有可能
Inner peace. Inner peace. Inner peace.
心平气和! 心平所和!
Peace on.
人条和气顺晒!
- Oh, Po? - Peace!
阿实!
Oh, Po, I got you a travel pack.
阿实! 我售你执咏行李
I packed you food for weeks. Cookies, buns, vegetables.
几个礼拜咀食物: 饼乾、急头、蔬菜
And I even packed all your action figures. See?
仲撰埋你哟模型，嫉吓?
I don't know what those are. Never seen them before in my life.
我唔知呢哟傈只，成世未见过
Dad, you got scratches on my Tigress.
阿移，你乔花我焦飞虎女啦!
l also packed your paintings of our best time together,
仲有记载我哟快弧时光咕…
just in case you get lonely.
万一你寂寞都可以望吓
That's me and you making noodles. And that's me and you eating noodles.
有我同你一羌整东、一竟食类
And that's me giving you a piggyback ride.
仲有我界你骑牛牛
That cute? On second thought, I'll hang on to this one.
得意哮? 我诊我都傈留返呢幅
- Hey, they're waiting for me. - Of course, of course.
喂，伍哎等紧我 傈
You have a job to do... far from home,
你有使命要完成，要识乡别井
in a strange city, filled with strange people, and strange noodles,
去陌生城市 对住阳生面孔、阳生烦
facing horrible danger from which you might never return!
要面对致命危机，未必返到唉
- Don't go, Po! - 1 gotta go.
唔好去啦! 阿寅! 我要去
I'm the Dragon Warrior. It's kind of my job to save kung fu.
我傈龙战士，要维护武林
And if I don't... what am I?
如果唔傈…我算傈净个?
You're my son.
你傈我个乖仔
Right?
傈趴?
- Po, it's time. - Goodbye.
阿实，傈时候啦 再见
Don't worry, Mr. Ping.
唔使愁
He'll be back before you can say “noodles.”
你未讲完个大字 但已经返喉见你面
Noodles.
葡
Come on, guys, let's go!
只图各位，出发!
Mama?
娘亲?
Mom? Dad? Is that you?
阿娘! 阿欧! 傈咪你哟呀?
Oh, hi. Hey, son. You're back.
阿仔，你返嘎嗓
Honey, what are you doing here?
乖仔，你返唉做昱呀?
We replaced you, dear, with this lovely radish.
我哟用呢叶可爱莹和萄代替咏你
- Radish? - It's quiet, polite, and, frankly,
衣萄? 伍斯文有礼
does better kung fu.
功夫仲员过你
No. No, no, no.
唔好! 唔好!
Wait!
等阵!
Radish, radish, radish, radish.
衣葡! 药萄!
Inner pea...
心平…
Inner peace.
心平气和
Inner peace! Inner peace! Inner peace! Inner peace! Inner peace...!
心平所和! 心平气和! 心平所和!
The mast is not a worthy opponent.
船杆喇配做你对手
- 1am ready. - OK.
放马过嗓畴! 好
So serious.
哇认真
I think I prefer the mast.
我情愿打梳船杆
Apologies. I used to punch the ironwood trees by the palace to train.
对喇住，我惯咕打 翡怪宫旁稳棵铁木栅练拳
Now I feel nothing.
而家右晒感沈
That's severely cool.
真傈犀飞利呀!
Again!
再唉哟!
So, this punching ironwood trees, how long did you have to do that?
只样打铁木榭练功 你张嘎伙耐?
- Twenty years. - Oh, 20, 20 years.
20年!
Is there any, you know, faster way?
有右速成方法?
You know, until you, you know, don't feel anything?
可以快哟练到有上晒感沈?
...[ don't think hard style is your thing.
我沈得硬功唔多员你
Po, why are you really out here?
阿实，点解你走出唆?
I just found out that my dad isn't really my dad.
我喷发现我阿驳 唔傈真傈我阿驳
Your dad? The goose.
你阿驳? 咽焦骗?
That must have been quite a shock.
啦你一定沉得好震移
Yeah.
傈
- And this bothers you? - Are you kidding me?
所以你就好心烦? 你讲笑只?
We're warriors, right? Nerves of steel.
我哟傈战士 筋骨似钢
Like you.
好似你
So hard-core, you don't feel anything.
几硬泽，完全有感沈
- 1 was... - So, what are you guys talking about?
你吡倾只呀?
Nothing. Nothing.
有有，话咀
Po's having daddy issues.
阿实烦紧阿欧骂事
I'm so lucky. I don't have any problems with my dad.
我就好彩，从来有阿驳问题
Maybe it's because Mom ate his head before I was born.
我未出世阿怒就吞中但个头
- 1 don't know. - Mantis, this isn't about you.
猛逮螂，唔天你事啦
Po is the one freaking out.
头奋看咽个傈阿裤
-I'm not freaking out. - Po.
我有头奉奋
- I'm freaking in. - Po!
我傈头岳后 阿实!
- What? - We're here.
吓? 我哟到咬!
Gongmen City.
傈言门城
My father's throne.
我阿驳吼实座
He used to let me play here beside him,
但以前界我吃伍侧净陪信玩
promising someday, this throne would be mine.
答应有日会传位界我
A little to the left.
再过哟左净
Oh, but it's so heavy, Master!
但傈伍好重呀，主人!
Thirty years I've waited for this moment.
我花咏30年等呢一刻
Everything must be exactly how I envisioned it.
每个细节都要同我想像一样
And I envisioned it a little to the left.
喉我想像中佰要再过哟左冰
Perfect!
好极!
With the weapon by my Si... A little bit more.
有了呢件武器吃我…再过哟
With the weapon by my side, all of China will bow before me.
有了呢件武器吃我身逮 全中原都要跪拜我
We move out in three days,
3日后出发
when the moon is full and the tide is high.
到时月圆… 潮水高涨
Now, you old goat, why don't you tell me my...
老喇，不如你算吓我吸…
Fortune?
命运?
Future. I was going to say future.
未来! 我傈想讲 「未来]
Look into your bowl and tell me what glory awaits.
嫉吓你焦碗 话我知我会有炎威
If you continue on your current path...
你继续行你而家最路…
. you will find yourself at the bottom of the stairs.
就会发现自己… 走到去楼梯底
I see...
我见到…
I see pain... and anger.
我见到你痛 仲有愤怒
How dare you! That is the finest silk in the province!
你大脆! 伍傈全省最靓咕布
Followed by denial.
然后你否定我
This is not fortune-telling. You're just saying
呢哟唔傈占卜，你讲吕都傈…
- what's happening right... - Now?
当下咀事?
The most important time is now.
最重要咀时刻就傈当下
But if you really want to see the future...
不过如果你真傈想预视未来…
Oh, what do you see?
你嫉到只?
A peacock...
有焦孔逢…
.. iS defeated by a warrior of black and white.
界个黑白战士打低
Nothing has changed.
蕊都有有改变
That's impossible, and you know it.
根本有有可能，你应该知
It is not impossible, and he knows it.
唔傈有可能，便都知
Who?
净个但?
- Lord Shen! I saw a panda! - A panda?
沈老大! 我见到和焦熊猫! 熊猫?
A kung fu warrior. It fought like a demon!
傈功夫战士! 出招鬼听快!
Big and furry.
又大又多毛
Soft and squishy. Kind of plush and cuddly.
仲软淋淋 似乎好好揽
There are no more pandas.
世上应该有了晒熊猪
Even with his poor eyesight, he can see the truth.
就算伍盲咏焦上限，都上嫉到真相
Why is it that you cannot?
点解你晓唔到?
Find this panda and bring him to me!
揭焦熊猫出喉，带伍见我
Yes, sir!
遵命!
One panda lives. That does not make you right.
有焦熊猪未死，啦唔代表你史
You're right. Being right makes me right.
你讲得吵 我之所以嘴傈因为我中
Then I will kill him and make you wrong.
哇我就狗埋但，证明你销
Will you stop that!
停呀!
That must be Shen's palace on the other side of the city.
对面应该就傈沈老大咀宫殿
Great. We'll march into the tower and proclaim,
好! 我吨征入城宣优:
“We are the Dragon Warrior and the Furious Five,
龙战士同蕾世五侠嗓制裁你!
What are you doing? This place is crawling with wolves.
你做只呀? 座城周围都傈狼
Hey, isn't that the guy who hammered you in the face?
伍咪傈打你才面咽焦狼?
I do not like that guy.
我习死响休友
We need to get to that tower without being spotted by those wolves.
要静静去座塔，咪界班狼发现
Got it. Stealth mode.
收到，用隐身入
Now, where'd those noodles go?
哟区去咏净?
Hello. I couldn't help but...
你好，我忍喇住导得…
Yeah, OK. Anyway, where was I?
好，搞搞…我吃净?
- Where's Po? - How can we lose a guy that big?
阿实吃净? 听大和焦都会喇见?
Guys! Guys?
喂! 喂?
- Hey, Po. - What? Sorry.
阿实 对喇住
So that was stealth mode, huh?
哈就叫隐身术?
To be honest, not one of my stronger modes.
我认，隐身喇傈我踢项
...gold in there, come on!
你应该促有金，界我
This rice is raw!
碗饭未熟!
You stole all my metal pots for Lord Shen!
你呈抢晒哟煲做铁弹
Either you cook my rice, or I cook you!
你唔者熟哟饭，我就煮咏你
- My apologies, but... - Po, do something.
阿实，想办法哎
How am I supposed to help her cook rice without getting caught?
有哇办法敬伍煮饭又唔被捉?
- Wait, I have a better idea. -...two...
等等，我有个更好最主意
one.
一
We're here to liberate the city and bring Shen to justice.
我吨嗓解放呢座城 制裁沈老大
- You will need help. - Thank you, brave sheep,
你哟要人党手 多谢，你好勇敢
but it's too dangerous. I can't let you.
但傈太危阶
Oh, no, not me. It's not safe to speak here.
唔傈讲我，呢度倾偶喇安全
Right.
吵!
I'm talking about Masters Ox and Croc.
我傈讲风暴牛同凶鲁大师
They're in Gongmen Jail on Black Dragon Alley.
但吡喉黑龙巷咀宫门监狼
What? They're still alive?
伍呈未死?
They must be in that jail gathering intelligence,
伍呈醒傈喉度搜集情报…
hatching a plot to use their awesomeness to defeat the weapon!
筹备紧剧除件武器
OK, let's go!
好，行图!
- Thanks, sheep. - Hey! Stop that costume!
多谢呀，羊生! 截停咽人条节!
- Hold it right there! - Get them!
提住但吨!
- Sorry!
对喇住!
Take that!
接招!
- Keep going! - Faster!
继续行图! 快哟!
- Look out! Watch it! - Sorry!
嫉住!
Now!
仲唔落手!
Gotcha!
搞拓!
- Spread out! Search everywhere! - What about over there?
分头揭! 度度都咪走漏! 咽度呢?
-Is “there” a part of "everywhere"? - I... [guess.
[度度」 包喇包唤度? 包哇
Then search there!
哇就揭埋唤度障!
They must be close. I can feel a kung fu chill riding up my spine.
伍吡喉附近 我背稍感质有股寒气
Sorry, Po. It's just me.
对唔住，阿寅，傈我
Look. Gongmen Jail.
嫉吓! 宫门监洗
Aw, it's cute.
好得意
Cute, huh?
得意?
Nice work, Po.
做得好，阿鹤
At the first sign of trouble, I'll give you a signal.
一有唔妥，我就发讯号
- You mean like Crane does? - Yeah.
似足仙鹤只叫? 傈
Excuse me, when have I ever made that noise?
咪住，我各有只样叫过”
Master Ox! Master!
牛大师! 大师!
The ferocious Master Croc!
况猛咀凶蟹大师!
And Master Storming Ox.
仲有风暴牛大师 !
I can't believe we're rescuing actual legends of kung fu.
唔敢相信我会亲手地救 武林奇人
We're gonna free you from those bonds of injustice. No problem.
我吨带你吡离开呢个黑狱…
Gotta be a key around here. No, they wouldn't leave a key around here.
有锁匙啦? 浆，仁吡有留低
Oh, good! You found it. Come on, you guys! Yeah!
好，你揭到 噬啦，嘱!
We're coming for you, Shen!
我哟噬啦，沈老大
Guys, are we going or not? Do you want to meet us there later?
你吡走唔走呀? 膛哟先会合?
I mean, you do want to take back your city, right?
你吡想擒返座城味?
Of course we do.
相上 YA 。，
But if we stand up to Shen, he will turn the weapon on the city.
但傈对付沈老大… 便就会用件武器对付座城
Listen to yourself. You're protecting Gongmen City
唔保护宫门城
by not protecting Gongmen City?
傈为吓保访宫门城?
- If we all fight together... - Then the weapon would kill everyone.
只要我呈联手… 件武器就会六上晒大家
Oh, would it? Then we use... a sneak attack!
傈? 只我哟… 偷开啦!
- We get inside and then... - And then you will be stopped...
注入去… 你会被阻止
...by the unstoppable weapon.
你阻喇住咽件武器
Nothing's unstoppable except for me when I'm stopping you
右吧傈阻喇住，除咏我… 我要阻止你
from telling me something's unstoppable!
话有吵傈阻喇住
Master Ox, I'm not letting you stay in this cell.
牛大师，我唔界你留吃因室
I'd like to see you get me out!
有本事你就超我出去
You guys see that? It's called being awesome.
见唔见呀”啦就叫扩!
Come on! Whatever happened to being heroes?
你吡喇傈大侠只?
The only hero in this town is a dead one!
呢座城唯一咀大侠已经死嘎
Like I said, you are not getting me out of this cell!
都话呼 你右闪法赶我出呢个囚室
Yes!
好喇!
All right, let's go!
好! 我哟行啦!
I get the top bunk.
我要央上格
It's time to surrender, panda. Kung fu is dead.
傈时候认输，能和猫 功夫玩完只
Kung fu is dead? Fine!
功夫玩完? 好!
You stay in your prison of fear with bars made of hopelessness.
你吡留吃恐悍囚室 对住绝望铁柱
And all you get are three square meals a day of shame!
每日三餐食咀肉傈 「辽友
With despair for dessert.
甜品叫 [心太灰]
We'll take on Shen and prove to all those who are hungry
我哟会对付沈老大 向追求正义棠耀咀好汉…
Yeah!
好喇!
Monkey?!
里猴!
You! You're mine!
你，我食硬你!
I'll tell you what's gonna be yours!
话你知你会食只!
My fist in your plush, cuddly, super-soft face!
你块面会食正我咀拳头!
Get him!
捉住伍!
- Get me out of here! - Yes, sir!
带我离开 ! 傈
Stop him!
截住伍!
Faster!
快哟!
Yeah! Go, go!
去图!
- Lose him! - Yes, sir!
搬甩便! 爸!
- Viper! - Hang on!
毒蛇! 捉实呀!
- What? - Watch out!
嫉住!
Uncool! Very uncool!
唔更! 好唔更!
Try this!
看招啦!
Guys, guys, guys!
嫉住! 嫉住…
Maybe something smaller!
细细粒，唔易食!
No, no! Oh, no, no.
停手! 停手!
Cute bunnies, off the face. Excuse me! OK, pardon me!
乖免仔唔好搞我才面! 借焉!
Fire!
火!
We've lost them.
喇见嘎伍吡!
Again! Again!
噬多次! 唉多次!
Crane, catch!
仙窒! 接住!
Gotcha!
搞拓!
Guys, guys, guys, guys, give me a shove!
推我一喇央!
Mantis, now!
独星时，嗓呼!
Is that all you got? It feels like I'm fighting a big old fluffy cloud!
傈得听多? 我觉得好似同史雪打
Well, this cloud is about to bring the thunder!
了呢嘲去好快会行雷!
Your turn!
到你畴!
Why... are... there... so... many... signs?!
点解有只多招牌?
Come here! Alaka-squasho!
噬呼! 压扁你!
Yes! Taste the defeat!
好! 输得甘啦?
Let me tell you something.
下次同熊猫玩，最好带多哟…
Guess nobody told you,
有人话你知?
if you mess with the wolf, you get the fangs.
得罪狼，狼会咬住你
I've hit you twice. What are you going to do now?
我打过你两次，你可以点?
We surrender!
我吨投降
You can chain my body, but you will never chain my... warrior spirit.
你锁得住我个身 锁唔住我蝶…侠客精神
- Hey, don't forget the little guy. - Did you just call...?
唔好漏焦豆钉 你叫我做…
- Po, what are you doing? - Trust me. I got a pl...
阿实，你做只呀? 信我啦，我有个…
No way. Eight-point acupressure cuffs?
喇傈嘛? 傈八卦封穴手鱼?
Just like the ones that held Tai Lung. The more you move, the tighter they get.
即傈锁大鹏响款 越择扎越锁得紧
These are the best cuffs!
傈最属害咀手钳
Greetings, panda. At last we meet!
你好，能和猫 终於，我兄面图
No, no, no...
唔好，唔好
We meet at last! Yes, that's it.
我哟见面啦，终於! 好，就啦!
Greetings, panda. We meet at...
你好，能和猫，我呈见面…
- You are afraid for a reason. - 1am not afraid.
你听敬休有原因 我有有敬
He is coming to me in chains.
但带住手鱼唉见我
- If anyone should be afraid, it's... - You.
往咕应立傈… 你
Don't even think about it.
你咪驶旨意 !
I hope this turns out better than your plan to cook rice in your stomach
希望今次个计划好过…
by eating it raw and then drinking boiling water.
上次你煮饭吞生米再饮滚水
This plan's nothing like that plan.
今次个计划喇同
- How? - ‘Cause this one's going to work.
点唔同? 今次会成功
Keep moving.
继续行
Ah, my old enemy...
我最宿襄
.. Stairs.
楼梯!
Thanks for carrying me those last few flights. OK.
唔该你驯我行最尾伙层
I threw up a little bit on the third floor.
我吃三楼哎嘎
Someone might want to clean that up.
应该有人清理
Is there some sort of evil janitor or something?
有右奸人去抹地?
Greetings, panda.
你好，能和猫
- We meet at... - Hey, how you doing?
我哟见面… 喂，你点呀?
Hey.
喂!
You've grown up bigger than I thought.
你长大咕，比我想像更大焦
Hey... enough with the poking around.
入锡啦
Strong. Healthy.
强壮! 嗯? 健康
Look, I don't know who you are, but please stand aside, sir.
我唔识你，借焉啦，先生
- That's a lady. - Oh! Sorry.
傈文士 对喇住
The beard threw me. It's kind of misleading.
你哟颇误半我
- False advertising. - Enough of this nonsense!
令我搞销 讲够废话啦!
Bring the prisoners to me.
押班俘锚过嗓!
Sorry, ma'am. Get ready, guys.
唔好意思，准人备!
Keep your eyes peeled for the... weapon!
忌大对了眼揭武器
Sparrow kick!
燕子回梨踊!
We did it! I just kung fu-ed it! Did you guys see that? I was all like...
得咏! 我用功夫搞掉佰!
Do you actually believe this is the warrior destined to defeat me?
你信便真傈会打低我?
I do not. I know he is.
喇傈信，傈知道
Oh, look at him. A lifetime to plot his revenge
嫉吓伍 成世想报仇
- and he comes to me on his knees. - What? A lifetime?
但而家要跪吃我面前 吓? 成世?
I did not have a lifetime.
我右成世想报仇
We only heard about Master Rhino a few days ago,
前伙日知犀牛大师咀死
- and we came to avenge him! - You've come to avenge nothing else?
先要报仇 你右其他仇要报?
Well, yeah. All the pots and pans that you stole.
有:! 你吡抢咏哟煲同猎
- I'm gonna want those back. - Nothing else?
我要搬返 右其他喇?
You probably did some other evil stuff along the way. I don't know.
你吡可能有其他衰喇 我喇知
- What else did you do? - You don't know?
你吡仲做喧只? 你唔知?
Know what? What's so funny?
知昱呀? 有呼好笑?
The very thing that you clearly do not know!
笑你重要吕咖反而唔知
OK, enough of these riddles! Would you guys spill the beans?
打锡哑谜啦，你吡从实招来
First, we come in and the weapon is tiny. Surprise, it's big.
我哟见件武器好细 点知原来好大
And then the lady over here, I think it’s a guy, ‘cause he's got...
然后咽位女士，我当咏傈大叔
The only reason you are still alive
你而家仲未死只傈因为…
is that I find your stupidity mildly amusing.
我觉得你超低能得噬劲搞笑
Well, thank you. But I find your evilness extremely annoying.
多谢 我汉得你超低装得吵劲搞事
Who do you think you are, panda?
你当你傈净个呀? 熊猫?
Who do you think I am, peacock?
你话我傈净个时? 孔私?
Why are we laughing?
笑昱呀?
Take aim.
瞄准!
Fire.
天火!
Well, light the... thing!
点著伍呀!
I did!
明明点嘎!
Fear the bug!
无大虹螂源!
Get the weapon!
搞扯件武器!
Tigress!
和飞虎女!
You... You were there.
咽时你喉度!
Yes. Yes, I was.
傈，我在场!
- You just let Shen get away! - At least we destroyed the weapon.
你界沈老大走甩咏! 至少毁减趾件武器
Fire!
天火!
Oh. No, he’s got way more.
浆! 伍促有好多
- My wing! - Help, Po!
我焦辟! 异手! 阿宽!
Coming!
噬紧 !
- Watch out! - Po!
嫉住呀!
- Help me up! - No. Get him down.
拉我上去! 唔好! 放伍落去
Use the ropes.
用强逃走!
Run, run, little panda!
走啦，熊猫仔!
- Po, come on. We need you to focus! - 1 got it, I got it!
阿实，喷! 集中精神! 我得咀
Bring it down!
打生但!
- We're trapped! - This way!
右路走! 呢稳
Goodbye!
再见!
Fire!
发射!
Get back!
返咯!
The only way out is up.
唯一出路傈上面
Follow me! Come on!
跟我只! 嗓哟!
Where are they going?
伍呈想去净?
- To the top! - Come on! Keep going!
上塔顶! 唔好停!
Here we go!
我哟内图 !
- You idiot! - My nose!
你个蠢材! 我个鼻!
Call in the wolves! All of them! I want them ready to move!
召集狼群! 全仙准人备出发!
The Year of the Peacock begins now!
而家起就傈孔誉年
Right now? ‘Cause it's the middle of the year,
而家?” 吃正一年中间喝
so you'd only get like a half of the Year of the Peacock.
只你个孔雀年咪得半年
And this is the Year, of course, of the Peacock.
今年就傈孔尖年
Happy New Year, sir.
新年快纪
Get the wolves ready. We're loading the ships now.
狼群准备，运武器上船
Now!
即刻!
Now, now, now, now, now!
即刻! 即刻!
Move! Move, move, move, move!
快哟! 快哟!
This way.
呢稳
Let's go.
走啦
What did you do? It's chaos up there.
你做咏只? 全城大天 !
What happened to stopping Shen?
你唔傈阻止沈老大只?
Yeah.
傈呀
Guys, come on. Give me a little credit.
各位! 唔该信吓我!
I meant for him to get away.
我故意放伍走
‘Cause... it was a trick. It was a plot.
装伍弹弓，傈仿局
I was thinking... I'll figure out his plot more.
哈会拆穿但个局
That makes no sense.
完全讲唔通
What do you mean? Sure it does.
梗傈通图
Po, the truth. You had Shen. What happened?
讲真话咬! 你捉咕伍，点解放人?
What are you talking about? I don't know what you're talking about.
吓? 我唔知你讲呼
I... Yeah... OK, he caught me off guard.
傈，伍趁我分心走甩
The truth.
真话!
Fine. They will keep you far from danger.
好 伍哎会嫉实你
- Real far. - What?
实一实 吓?
You're staying here.
你要留低
Wait! I have to go ba...
等等! 我要返去…
I'm going. And you can't stop me.
我要去! 你阻我喇住!
OK. I wasn't ready that time.
喘叶我未准备好
Guys? Don't.
老友，咪打呼!
Look!
嫉住!
Stay down.
唔好打
-l have to get to him. - Then tell me why!
我要揭便! 话我匠点解
He was there! OK?
当时住在场! 得未?
The peacock was there the last time I saw my parents.
我最后见父母时 焦孔和耀噬度
He knows what happened. Where I came from.
但知发生只事，知我身世
Who I am.
知我傈净个
Look, I'm going.
我要去
I have to know.
要知道真相
The hard core can't understand.
你哈硬泽唔会明白
Tigress, no!
飞虎女，唔好!
The hard core do understand.
硬泽，都可以明明
But I can't watch my friend be killed.
但我唔可以晓住朋友送死
- We're going. - Maybe you can't watch me be killed?
我吨走 巧你可以嫉住我送死?
- Stop being a wimp. - And she's back.
咪腾蕉啦 伍又做返自己
- No. - Don't worry, kid.
唔使愁喝
You're better off here.
你留喉度仲好
You were wrong, Soothsayer. We sail to victory tonight.
你错晒，天机女 我哟今晚旗开得膀
Your magic panda is clearly a fool.
你焦神奇熊猫根本傈春材
Are you certain it is the panda who is a fool?
你沈得售熊猫傈蠢材?
You just destroyed your ancestral home, Shen.
你跨拆咏自己间祖屋
A trivial sacrifice... when all of China is my reward.
小小和怕牲嗜… 好快我会得到成个中原
Then will you finally be satisfied?
啦你就会心足?
Will the subjugation of the whole world finally make you feel better?
你得到全天下就开心?
It's a start. l might also convert the basement into a dungeon.
起码傈个开始
The cup you choose to fill has no bottom.
你最野心有如和无底深潭
It is time to stop this madness.
傈时候停止呢种疯狂行为
Why on earth would I do that?
点解呀?
So your parents can rest in peace.
啦你父母至会安息
My parents hated me.
我父母异我
Do you understand?
你明白嘛?
They wronged me... and I will make it right.
但哎嫉销咕我 我要证明我虽
They loved you.
伍呈好爱你
They loved you so much that having to send you away killed them.
所以送你走之后就伤心到死
The dead exist in the past... and I must tend to the future.
死嘎就喇好再提 我要创造自己咀未来
Set the soothsayer free. She's no use to me.
放走天机娘 便已经有利用价值
Goodbye, Shen. I wish you happiness.
和后会有期，我希望你会幸福
Happiness must be taken.
幸福傈靠自己争取
And I will take mine.
我实会种取到
- Hurry it up! - Move it!
快哟!
If all of those weapons leave the building, China will fall.
批武器有运晒出去，中原实沦陷
- We bring down the building. - Hey, guys. How about this?
整寄呢度啦 不如用伍叶?
- This will work! - All right, let's go.
应该有用 好，我哟去
I can't feel my face.
我顽面有了晒知觉
Did you hear him call it Year of the Peacock?
避到伍叫今年做孔誉年嘛?
- Hey.
喂!
OK. So, keep it cool. Keep it cool. Keep it cool.
镇定响，镇定响
You! Where are you going?
你! 你去净呀?
On your feet! And wipe those stupid grins off your faces.
企定! 咪再笑到烩熟狗头
Move, you dogs! Faster, faster! Load them all!
郁手，走狗! 快哟! 运晒上船!
Greetings, panda.
你好，能和猫
- Tell me what happened that night. - What night?
话我知咽晚发生昱事 站上晚?
- That night. - Ah, that night.
咽晚! 哦，咽晚!
Yes! We're talking about the same night, right?
傈! 我吡讲紧同一晚啦?
Yes, I was there. Yes. I watched as your parents abandoned you.
傈，我在场! 嫉住你父母遗奉你
It's a terrible thing. I believe it went something like this.
真险功 我诊咽种痛就好似哇
Here's your New Year's gift.
你咀贺年礼物 !
Hope you like it, ‘cause you can't return it.
希望你锤意，因为有得退货
Po? What's he doing here?
阿实? 伍噬度做只?
Return it! Return it!
退货呀! 退货呀!
Are you willing to die to find the truth?
你死都要知道真相?
You bet Il am. Although I'd prefer not to.
右错! 不过最好唔吏死啦
We got them. Go!
我吡搞振，你上啦!
You looking for me?
你揭紧我?
I said that too soon, didn't I?
我讲得早得溃，傈嘛?
Po!
阿实!
Po, get away from him.
阿实! 识开但呀!
I'll get up. Here we go.
我会上去…喷哟
- No more running, Shen. - So it seems.
跑锡啦，沈老大 嫉嗓傈
Now... answers.
即刻答我
Oh, you want to know so badly.
你真傈好想知喝
You think knowing will heal you, huh?
你以为知咕会好过哟?
Fill some crater in your soul?
填补到你心四咀空虚?
Well, here's your answer.
答案就优…
Your parents didn't love you.
你父母唔爱你
But here...
不过啦…
...let me heal you!
我会医好你!
No!
唔好呀!
Yeah, like you could make me drink that.
你以为我会饮?
If ! wanted you dead, I would have left you in that river.
我想你死就由得你贞喉人条河图
- Well, why save me? - So you can fulfill your destiny.
点解救我? 等你可以完成使命
What are you talking about? Where am I?
你讲只呀? 我傈净度?
What is this place?
呢度傈昱地方?
I'm surprised you remember so little.
估喇到你记得只少
But you were so little when it happened.
不过难怪，你当时只细
Perhaps you do remember.
可能你其实记得
What? It's just a stupid nightmare.
只傈个低能恶葛
Nightmare? Or memory?
恶萝?抑或记屋?
This was a thriving village.
呢度曾经傈繁盛村硅
Young Shen was in line to rule Gongmen City.
沈老大本来会继承宫门城
But he wanted more.
不过但唔心足
I foretold that someone would stand in his way. A panda.
我预言会有个侠士阻止但 傈焦熊和猿
But I never could have foretold what came next.
不过我预知唔到跟住发生明事
Get them all!
搞拓晒伍吨!
Take our son and run away! Go!
带埋阿仔快哟走! 走央!
Stop fighting. Let it flow.
唔好抗拒，由得记屋浮现!
Your story may not have such a happy beginning,
你骂故事开头可能唔多开心…
but that doesn't make you who you are.
但你优昱人，唔受出身影响
It is the rest of your story.
傈由以后你做咀事决定
Who you choose to be.
由你咀玩择决定
So, who are you, panda?
好，你傈净个? 熊猫?
lam Po.
我傈阿鹤
And I'm gonna need a hat.
我要戴顶帆
Such sad, sad faces.
苦口苦面
But now is a time only for joy.
而家应该天开心心
You are going to be part of something beautiful.
难得你呈参加到一场美琳盛事
Once we reach the harbor, in front of all the world,
一到码头，全世界都会嫉到…
you and your precious kung fu will die.
你同你呈最实具功夫玩完
Then China will know to bow before me.
然后全中原都会跪拜我
Set sail!
起销!
Honestly, guys, I never thought I'd die like this.
讲真，我有论过咱死法
l always thought I'd meet a nice girl and settle down and...
我以为会遇到靓女，安定落嗓
..then she'd eat my head.
然后界但食咏我个头
- So sad. - We cannot give up hope.
险功 咪放训希望
Po would want us to remain strong. Hard-core. Right, Tigress?
阿实会想我吡捞住 要硬泽，傈路?和飞虎女?
- Lord Shen, what about the bridge? - Nothing stands in my way.
沈老大，休橘点算? 右呈可以阻住我
Fire!
天火!
You coward!
你个惨夫!
Po?
阿实?
How many times do! have to kill the same stinking panda?
我要儿同一焦臭熊猫 几多次至锡?
Shen!
沈老大!
A panda stands between you and your destiny.
有焦熊猫喉你同你吸…
What?
吓?
Prepare yourself for a hot serving of justice.
你等住喉吓热辣辣邑…
- What? - And now, free the Five!
即刻…放晒五侠!
Disc of Destruction!
减绚飞环!
OK. Take aim!
好嘲! 瞄准!
Ready?
得未?
You can't follow me.
你追我唔到
Just get him!
做低但图 !
- Yeah. Here we go. - Come on!
噬呼!
- No, no, no, don't shoot! - Don't shoot!
停! 唔好射呀!
- You don't shoot! - 1 won't shoot if you won't shoot.
你唔好射 你唔射我唔射
- Don't shoot! Cross fire! - Attack!
唔好射! 因住怠火! 攻蝇啦!
- Catch of Freedom! - Monkey!
接住有身! 里猴!
Impressive, Dragon Warrior. What's your plan?
精彩，龙战士，你有只大计?
- Step one, free the Five. - What's step two?
第一步: 放晒五侠 第二步呢?
Honestly, I didn't think I'd make it this far.
讲真，我有论过找到噬呢度
Stop Shen before he gets to the harbor.
阻止沈老大，喇界伍出潜口
Nice!
好喇!
Viper, Puppet of Death!
毒蛇，强身倪偶术!
Tigress!
和飞虎女!
- Master Ox! - Jump!
牛大师!
- And Croc! - Vengeance is served.
仲有凶犹! 有报必贫!
- Why did you...? - Your friend there is very persuasive.
点解你哟… 你位朋友好有说服力
Master Shifu!
施福师傅!
Quickly. Use their boats to block the way.
快哟! 用伍吡咀船描路!
Crane!
仙宁!
Wings of Justice!
大侠展翅!
What?
吓?
I love you guys.
我最键意你吡!
Why aren't we firing?
做只唔开火呀?
They're taking out our gunners, sir. They're getting close.
伍哎搞搞咏好多炮手 杀紧埋吧!
Fire! Fire at them!
开火! 射但噶!
- But, sir, we'll kill our own. - I said fire at them!
哈会欠埋班手足 我话射但吡呀!
Fire!
天火!
No.
唔得!
Po!
阿实!
Tigress?
和飞虎女?
As you wish.
如你所原
Let's finish this.
了结伍图!
Fire!
天火!
Inner peace.
心平气和
Again!
再吧!
Kill him! Somebody kill him!
狼咏伍! 针叶但呀!
What? No. No!
吓? 唔得!
Keep firing! Keep firing!
继续开火! 继续开火 !
How did you...?
你点会…
How did you do it?
你点会做得到?
You know, you just keep your elbows up and keep the shoulders loose.
提高手跑，放缀膊头
Not that. How did you find peace?
唔傈嘛，你点可以心平气和?
I took away your parents. Everything.
我令你有有了嘎父母，只都有有!
I scarred you for life.
令你生命留吓伤痕
See, that's the thing, Shen. Scars heal.
傈啦吸，沈老大，伤痕会好返
No, they don't. Wounds heal.
错，唔会，伤口先会好返
Oh, yeah. What do scars do? They fade, I guess?
傈?只伤痕会点? 会消退?
- 1 don't care what scars do. - You should, Shen.
我唔想知伤痕会点 ! 你应该想吓，沈老大
You gotta let go of that stuff from the past, ‘cause it just doesn't matter.
你要放低茧史 蔷史已经唔重要
The only thing that matters is what you choose to be now.
重要咀傈你选择从今以后要点
You're right.
你哮!
Then I choose... this!
我选择只样!
That was pretty hard-core.
你头先都伙硬泽!
- Po! - You did it!
阿实!
- Come here! Yeah! - Don't ever do that again, please.
噬啦 下次唔好再试
It seems you have found inner peace.
嫉嗓你领悟到心平气和之道
And at such a young age.
果然英雄出少年
Well, I had a pretty good teacher.
傈良师出高徒至真
What do you mean he's not here? It's my son's birthday.
只意思呀?伍唔喉度? 我个仔生日
All he wanted was to meet the Dragon Warrior.
但泽傈想唆暗龙战士
How about some tofu birthday cake instead, huh?
不如买哟豆腐恰包?
You know, I think we'll just try again another time.
我诊都傈下次再嗓
When do you think he'll be back?
但伙时返呀?
I don't know. OK, I don't know. Maybe never.
我唔知! 我唔知呀! 可能喇返!
I mean, I worry, OK? But that's my job, I'm his dad.
我好担心，但要顶住 我傈伍阿驳
At least, l was his dad.
至少我做过但阿欧!
Why did he have to go and save China? I know why.
点解伍要去拯救中原? 我知点解…
But why? He's just one little panda.
但傈点解喝? 伍只傈焦熊猫仔
So, how did it go? Did you save China?
点呀?你拯救到中原?
Yep.
傈呀!
Well, knew you would.
我知你实得
That's why I had new signs made.
所以做定新广告
“My son saved China. You, too, can save.
我秒仔救国救民，益埋你一份
Buy one dumpling, get one free.”
水饿圈一送一
Hey, that's a pretty good deal.
真傈好抵
- Would you like to try one? - Maybe later.
想唔想整返碗? 膛哟先图
There's something I should tell you.
我有喇要同你讲
While I was gone, I found the village where I was born.
我今次上路… 揭到我出世响人条村
I found out how I ended up in that radish basket.
知道我点解会去咏个苦葡篮度
You did?
你揭到?
- 1 know who lam. - You do?
我知道我傈净个 你知道?
I'm your son.
我傈你个仔
Il love you, Dad.
我爱你，阿驳
Il love you, too, son.
我爱你，乖仔
Delicious, fat radishes!
衣葡又大又更
You're probably hungry. Let me make you something to eat.
你实好肚臧 我煮吵界你食
What are you talking about? I'll cook.
你讲呼呀? 我煮至吵
- No, no, I'll cook. - Dad!
唔得，我煮 阿驳
Well, it's the least I can do. You saved China.
界我出分力，你救咏中原喝
No, it's the least I can do. You raised me.
界我出分力，你辩大我喝
- Po. - Dad.
阿实 阿驳
- Po! - OK.
好了图
Let's both cook. Together.
我呈一羌煮，拍硬档
Together.
拍硬档
No, I'll cook.
唔好，都傈我煮
My son is alive.
我个仔右死到 !
ENGLISH ESL
CANTONESE